<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<component>

    <name>InteractionNetwork</name>

    <version>1.0</version>

    <doc>
    	Produces an interaction network between input genes based on interactions stored in the Moksiskaan database. This component
    	is based on CandidateReport from Marko Laasko.
    </doc>

    <author email="christian.frech@ccri.at">Christian Frech</author>

    <category>Moksiskaan</category>
    <category>Pathway</category>
    <category>Reporting</category>

    <inputs>

       <input name="genes" type="IDList">
          <doc>Set of input genes as Ensembl stable identifiers</doc>
       </input>

       <input name="moksiskaan" type="Properties" optional="true">
          <doc>JDBC connection for Moksiskaan database</doc>
       </input>

       <input name="ensembl" type="Properties" optional="true">
          <doc>JDBC connection for Ensembl database</doc>
       </input>

       <input name="status" type="ActivityTable" optional="true">
          <doc>Status information for the genes</doc>
       </input>

       <input name="corrData" type="Matrix" optional="true">
          <doc>Gene activity measurements for the correlation analysis</doc>
       </input>

    </inputs>

    <outputs>

       <output name="report" type="Latex">
          <doc>Characterization of the given gene set</doc>
       </output>

       <output name="pathway" type="GraphML">
          <doc>Pathway topology for the candidate pathway</doc>
       </output>

    </outputs>

    <parameters>

        <parameter name="organism" type="int" default="9606">
            <doc>Organism of interest defined by NCBI Taxonomy identifier.
                 Default is Homo sapiens.</doc>
        </parameter>

        <parameter name="linkTypes" type="string" default="defaults">
            <doc>A comma separated list of identifiers of link types of interest or
                 'defaults' for the predefined set of supported links</doc>
        </parameter>

        <parameter name="bioentityTypes" type="string" default="">
            <doc>A comma separated list of bioentity types of interest.
                 An empty string refers to genes.
            </doc>
        </parameter>

        <parameter name="annotRules" type="string" default="">
            <doc>A comma separated list of optional link annotation rules.
                 Only those links are used that match at least one of the given rules.
                 Each rule is represented by a 'name=value' pair or a plain name if all values are accepted.
                 Values are in SQL LIKE syntax.</doc>
        </parameter>

        <parameter name="maxGap" type="int" default="1">
            <doc>Maximum number of genes between any two candidate genes
                 in their interaction network</doc>
        </parameter>

        <parameter name="hideGaps" type="boolean" default="false">
            <doc>Disables the rendering of the genes other than the given candidates</doc>
        </parameter>

        <parameter name="isolateGroupNames" type="boolean" default="false">
            <doc>Combined nodes of the pathway graph are labelled with artificial names described
                 in a separate table. This approach reduces the complexity of the actual figure.</doc>
        </parameter>

        <parameter name="expand" type="string" default="connected">
            <doc>Selection criterion for the related genes as described in CandidatePathway component.</doc>
        </parameter>

        <parameter name="statusFilter" type="string" default="">
            <doc>A comma separated list of gene statuses (NA,-1,0,1) of the genes that shall be
                 excluded from the candidate pathway if the status information is provided</doc>
        </parameter>

        <parameter name="useStudies" type="string" default="*">
            <doc>A comma separated list of study identifiers of the possibly interesting
                 results. An asterisk refers to all possible studies available.
                 An empty string disables the listing of relevant studies for the genes</doc>
        </parameter>

        <parameter name="showPathways" type="string" default="WikiPathways">
            <doc>A comma separated list of LinkAnnotation names providing pathway IDs.
                 The links provided by these pathway sources are shown on separate tables.</doc>
        </parameter>

        <parameter name="corrLimit" type="float" default="0.3">
            <doc>Absolute value of the correlation coefficient must be greater than this limit
                 it the correlation data is used to prune the candidate pathway.</doc>
        </parameter>

        <parameter name="cytoscape" type="boolean" default="false">
            <doc>Create a Cytoscape session for the candidate pathway and attach it to the report.</doc>
        </parameter>

        <parameter name="pathwayDesc" type="string" default="">
            <doc>An additional text that will follow the figure caption of the candidate pathway.</doc>
        </parameter>

        <parameter name="title" type="string">
            <doc>Latex section title for report.</doc>
        </parameter>

        <parameter name="sectionType" type="string" default="subsection">
            <doc>Latex section type for report.</doc>
        </parameter>

    </parameters>
</component>
